To a lot of people on the internet,
this right here looks absolutely fine as
far as
content. However, in time, I think
that the content you produce should look
like
this. And in this video,
I'm going to talk you through some of the
things that
people would never teach you unless you
paid them to do it.
Everything begins with making good
content.
If you can't make good content,
you can't get attention.
If you can't get attention,
you're not going to get people's data.
If you can't get the data,
you can't talk to them.
If you can't talk to them,
you can't send them to your sales page.
And if you can't send people to your sales
page, well you're not going to make
sales.
My name is James Smith.
I have nearly 5 million followers across
social media, and
this is a formula in
which I use to make banging content.
Now I bet when you see big expensive
lenses like this, and if we zoom out a bit
and show you the microphone
that we keep out of shot,
and then you see our
A camera, which has got an expensive
monitor on top of it.
Shit can get pretty overwhelming.
Not to mention,
if we cut from this audio to the audio
inside that camera,
you'll realize that even these expensive
cameras don't sound that great without
professional audio. So as a bare minimum,
you should probably get yourself a
shotgun microphone. Declan,
if you wouldn't mind.
But what if I was to tell you
that the camera, the audio, the setup,
the studio,
is actually probably one of the least
important parts of making great
content. It's important, but
if you really want to do well,
follow these steps.
The basics.
You're probably going to need an iPhone.
No offense to Android users,
but it's pretty obvious you're using an
Android.
And those of you that are using an iPhone,
if your iPhone is pre-pandemic,
people can tell. The second thing,
you will need some kind of professional
microphone. Audio is important.
I'm even now sacrificing good audio
just to mix things up a bit. These
are relatively expensive, but
let me show you.
These shitty Amazon wireless mics.
Those of you that use these, these
are literally worse than iPhone audio.
Terrible, awful. No excuses.
And you'll even notice that being very
softly spoken from very far away,
these wireless microphones can do a
tremendous job
of making you sound fantastic. It
is a small investment, but honestly,
when it comes to making a production,
which is what every single piece of
content
is, sometimes I think the audio
is more important than the video.
We want people to be able to listen to
what we're saying, and more importantly,
the
point that we're putting across.
If you're going to skimp on anything,
do not skimp
on the microphones you use. This
is how you connect with people.
So don't take audio lightly. It
is a big part of making amazing
content. One of the first
and most easy ways to make content
is to problem solve.
So what is a problem someone is facing?
Let's try and solve it.
Declan, put me on the spot.
Think of any niche, any business,
a problem someone
might face. So the problem
is someone's putting out content,
but they're not
getting business from it. Cool. So then
if someone's biggest problem is that
they're putting out content,
not getting business from it,
we need to turn that
into a hook. We could just say,
"If you're someone who's putting out
content,
but you're not getting business from it",
there are better ways to make this hook.
So,
you're someone who puts out content and
doesn't get business from it.
Let's think about hooks we can have with
this. If you're someone who
is consistently,
because then we can flatter them
a little bit, putting out great content,
but somehow at the end of the day,
you're not getting new clients from it,
then we can insert solution.
Then we might make another one.
How can we reframe this?
What if I was to tell you
that great content isn't enough on its
own to bring in new business?
So I now look at these two
and I could probably
agree, you might as well,
that the second one could be a little bit
better.
Or how about another one?
Imagine a world where you post great
content
in the evening and wake up with clients
and inquiries in
the morning.
Let's maybe look for a question hook,
which is posing a
question to someone.
Is it possible to post content that on its
own could bring us in new clients as we
sleep?
Let's even look for another one.
What type of content do you need to
post to get new clients? Let's keep going.
Statement hook.
You're posting the wrong type of content
to get new clients.
So now I'm creating different types of
hooks, different things,
and I'm looking at
them and thinking
which one would emotionally charge me the
most to take action.
I quite like the statement hook.
You're posting the wrong type of content
to get
new clients because it's actually
intertwined with the very point of the
video
we're making.
You're posting the wrong type of content
to get new clients.
Instead, you should focus on point, point,
point.
Probably deliver three different points.
You should focus on problem solving,
showing not telling, using
clever analogies to make the point. Cool.
Now, we can also use something like AI
or ChatGPT.
I'm trying to teach people about interest
rates on their
mortgage. Using a bag of frozen peas, what
kind of analogy, similes, and metaphors
could I use?
I think I got this one from Damian Talks
Money.
Big up, Damian. And as you can see here,
we're now getting some different ideas
that we could use. Now, to bolster
that hook, which is a statement hook or a
question hook or whatever it is,
and I know we veered into a slightly
different
category,
we could now use the bag of frozen peas to
get the point to camera.
This bag of frozen peas represents the
content you're putting out to win
over new clients.
This bag of frozen peas represents the
interest rate on your
mortgage. So with that statement,
with that hook,
there's going to be some kind of
inquisition. They're going to be like,
"Okay,
how is this person going to use this
bag of peas to help me understand it?"
Each one of these peas represents a piece
of
content, or for this.
Each one of these peas represents a pound
that you spent on
your mortgage each month, whatever it is.
We can actually go through here,
find out the metaphors, the similes, the
analogies, whatever it is.
We can then deliver the points of
information that we
want to about the video we're doing,
and we get out.
So that type of video, informative.
And we've curated the idea of
that video from a problem
that we know that people
have, like you said before. Now,
the second way that we could do it.
So many people think
that they can reinvent the wheel
and create new types of
content.
Even MrBeast isn't coming up with original
Ryan Trahan and MrBeast have copied videos
from other people in the past.
One of the best things we can do
is look to what is already working.
We can look for trends.
We can look for themes.
In the world of YouTube,
there's even a website here called One of
Ten, where you
can put in your competitors,
and it'll tell you
which one of their videos is
performing the best.
Another thing we can do is Ed Lawrence.
Are you spending a crazy amount of time
trying to grow a YouTube channel?
I actually am, Ed.
We can use vidIQ's plugin here,
and we can even see
which one of Ed's videos
are trending right now.
The reason that this is great
is we can see what his viewers
are interested in
right now. Now, some of these videos
are relatively new, but some of them
are quite
old.
This video here from nine months ago
is still doing the rounds.
So we can look at patterns.
And I'll be honest, 21 days ago,
Ed used a video
and it said, "I studied 1,000 YouTubers.
Here's why they can't make money." I saw
that Ed's video was performing
really well, so I made a video saying,
"I studied 1,000 businesses," and six
hours later,
Ed made another video saying he studied
1,000 YouTubers.
At the same time that I
was copying Ed's outlier title that
outperformed,
Ed was copying his own video outlier title
that performed well
before. We're narking.
We can also then use Instagram short-form
content
platforms to look for hooks
and trends that we might think would be
good
for our business.
What do you do about it? The sad truth
is that sebum- So
this video here, performing really well.
I like that the first thing used is,
"The sad truth is." So then we might not
want to talk about bodybuilding,
but we could go back to our ideation.
We could go statement hook,
the sad truth is.
Now, this might seem like a pretty
boring title,
but we can make so much out of this.
The sad truth is
that most newbie gains occur
before 30. The sad truth is most fitness
businesses don't survive their second
year.
The sad truth is that you should buy my
short-form content mastery course,
link in description.
And you could create so many videos where
this just starts with this.
Now, a good example of this,
you can tell I didn't plan this video.
There is a YouTube channel called Jimmy
the Giant. I've talked about this before.
Now, when we get onto Jimmy the Giant,
he has discovered buckets, and what I mean
by this is if we look at his trending
videos here, actually,
let's go to the most
popular. Britain's most hated subculture.
Russia's most hated subculture.
So again, he found a bucket here.
Which one did first?
Britain's most hated subculture.
He then just has to swap the word because
he has a recipe for something that's
working here.
Then one of the best things Jimmy the
Giant uses here is the evil
decline of.
The decline of Britain's failed Hitler,
the evil decline of Britain's
dystopian estates,
the death of Britain's most feared
subculture.
There are so many different titles here
that worked once for him, so he then
keeps using them. So if you
were to have a reel that said,
"The sad truth is," and
you were getting a good reaction from
starting a reel with that, you should 100%
continue using that hook. Now,
one of the most other popular ways to
create some kind of viral reel
is to react to something
that someone's putting out.
There are websites out there like SnapTik,
Instagram Downloader, so we can actually
download someone's reel to react to it.
So let's look at someone who isn't very
good looking,
Darren Cartel.
Let's say he posts something
that I want to react to.
Do you find it weird in jujitsu
[upbeat music] Cool,
so I can find the video. I'm not sure
if this is actually legal.
Is it legal to...?
Yeah. Now, it's probably always better
if you download it.
Now,
here is one of the most important things
when doing this.
So many people start their react video
with them just looking at their phone like
this.
Get something in there before you react to
it.
So for instance, are you feeling creative,
Declan?
Can you do two hands at the same time?
Press record on that one.
This is absolutely disgusting.
We can go to the clip,
then we're going to come
back.
How can you call this professionalism?
You're supposed to be stopping fires from
happening in the UK when it's -2 outside,
and instead,
you're letting mediocre influencers dive
down your
pole. It's absolutely abhorrent. Cheers,
Declan.
So now what we can do is we can take
that file that we found
before.
I can AirDrop it across to my phone,
and then we can use CapCut.
We
can start a new project using this.
This is absolutely disgusting. Cut.
We can scroll here.
Get this. This is absolutely disgusting.
[upbeat music]
Split, delete. How can you call this-
There you go. Look at this.
See how the sausage is made. Hey,
what would you like for dinner?
Fantastic. We're going to cut the gaps.
You're supposed to be stopping fires from
happening in the UK when it's -2
outside, and instead,
you're letting mediocre influencers dive
down your pole. It's absolutely abhorrent.
Cool. We can cut that.
We can stop that.
Make sure you delete the watermark off the
end.
We're going to go back to the beginning.
We're going to go Text.
We're going to go Auto Subtitles.
Subtitles are important.
Make them a little bit smaller,
bring them up close to the eye line,
then we can go
through them. We can make sure there
are any changes that need to be made,
then we
can export. That's very simply.
I know that so many of the things we're
saying
there don't really make sense, but
that should be the process of creating
content.
There are going to be several buckets of
content that you do.
Problem-solving, create a good hook,
have a good payoff.
We can react to people's stuff
that we agree with, that we disagree with.
We can download their videos.
We can credit them.
We can look at outliers from other people
within our niche, whether on YouTube,
other places. We can go to creators
and see what's trending within theirs.
Now,
we should not go into someone's transcript
and steal every word for word, but
we can take very good amounts of
inspiration from titles and thumbnails,
and
if you really do go too close to the
flame, just credit people for what you're
doing and say, "Look,
I saw this amazing video.
For that reason,
I'm going to do it." The majority of my
best ideas and my best
videos have been inspired by other things.
There is no such thing as original in this
game because whoever you're copying from
probably copied from someone else.
The thing is,
you must put your own twist on it.
When we look at Batman,
the most recent Batman, the one with
that fellow from
Twilight in, was the same one
that had Christian Bale in, which
was the same one
that had George Clooney in.
Batman's been done like five times,
but each director
puts their own twist on it. That
is what you can do with your content.
But this is the final
and biggest lesson for any of you
that want to dominate in
this game. Said it before,
I'll say it again.
You need to make 100 pieces of content as
fast as possible because chances are,
for the majority of you,
all of your next 100 videos
are going to suck, but then
the next 100 are going to suck a bit less,
and the next 100 are going to suck a
little bit less,
and the next 100 after that
are going to suck even less.
Then before you know it, people
are going to say you put out amazing
content.
There is so much information
that I can give you about curating hooks,
setups,
camera equipment, microphone,
all of these things, but nothing
is going to beat
you stumbling and fumbling
and course-correcting.
You're going to make videos you thought
were going to do amazing that bomb, then
you're going to make videos
that you're going to think bomb
that do amazing.
There is literally no other way around
this than practicing,
then falling forward,
then continue repetition. I have four
and a half thousand posts on Instagram,
which is like a post today for a decade.
So my two last pieces of advice for any of
you looking to make better content, make
more content.
It's the only way you're going to get
better at it.
The second thing is to buy my short-form
content creation mastery course.
We've only scratched the surface of some
of the things that you need to apply to
your business. It's 99 US dollars.
Use the link in the description, buy it,
and revolutionize your content game.
I don't think I have what it takes for you
to make the most amazing content in the
world.
I think you already have what it takes.
You just need me and my course
and this video to give you the confidence
to start,
because you're probably 1,000 videos away
from being fucking good at this.
My course will just give you the stepping
stones to doing the first few hundred.
You can take it from there. Enjoy.
I look forward to seeing your content on
my
Explore feed very soon. Bye-bye.